<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | </title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Distributions and Modelling of Finite Wireless Networks</title>
      <link>/project/distance_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/distance_distributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Distance distributions can be applied to study important wireless network characteristics such as interference, outage probability, connectivity, routing, and energy consumption. They can also be applied in other branches of science, such as forestry, mathematics, operations research and material sciences. When a fixed and finite number of nodes are uniformly and independently distributed over a finite region such as a square or hexagon (polygon in general), the two important distance distributions are: 1) the pdf of the Euclidean distance between two nodes uniformly and independently distributed inside a polygon and 2) the pdf of the Euclidean distance between any arbitrary reference point and its nth neighbor node when N nodes are uniformly and independently distributed inside a polygon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our key contributions are available here(&lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/software/)&#34;&gt;https://s-durrani.com/software/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Ultra‐Reliable and Sustainable Machine‐to‐Machine Communications</title>
      <link>/project/arc_mtom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arc_mtom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an ARC Discovery Project &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP170100939&#34;&gt;DP170100939&lt;/a&gt;. I was lead-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel solutions for data transmission, low-power backscatter transmission and wireless power transfer have been proposed to provide faster data rate, more reliable connectivity and prolonged network lifetime for machine-to-machine communications and Internet of Things devices and networks. The research outcomes were published in 27 journal papers and 20 conference papers. This includes several highly cited papers. The project involved successful collaboration with researchers from Canada, USA and Hong Kong. The project provided research training to one postdoc and 3 PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground Based IoT Sensor Networks for Wildfire Detection</title>
      <link>/project/bushfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/bushfire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic goal of this project is to develop an IoT (internet of things) ground-based sensor system to provide rapid detection of fires in their early stages. This project is funded through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://brcoe.org/project/ground-based-iot-sensor-networks/&#34;&gt;ANU Bushfire Research Centre of Excellence&lt;/a&gt;. The project has resulted in two journal papers and 1 conference paper so far, where I am a co-author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific contributions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survey paper on IoT Ground Sensing Systems for Early Wildfire Detection: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3501336&#34;&gt;[Magazine paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning based detection algorithm: &lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/publication/&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical detection algorithm: &lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/publication/&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Spherical Geometry in Scientific and Engineering Data Processing</title>
      <link>/project/arc_spherical_signal_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arc_spherical_signal_processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an ARC Discovery Project &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP150101011&#34;&gt;DP150101011&lt;/a&gt;. I was a co-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel solutions for sampling and spherical signal processing have been proposed to process data in real world applications such as biomedical imaging, astronomy and acoustic signal processing. The research outcomes were published in 8 journal papers and 12 conference papers. The project involved successful collaborations with researchers from Europe. The project provided research training to 4 postdocs and 2 PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD student and later postdoc Zubair Khalid was funded through this grant. Zubair Khalid was a part of the team which recently won the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://awards.acm.org/bell-climate&#34;&gt;Gordon Bell Prize for Climate Modelling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Wireless Networks</title>
      <link>/project/machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning is expected to play a key role in 6G wireless networks. Many of my past and current PhD students have used machine learning tools and paradigms in their research. This research work is carried out using &lt;a href=&#34;https://nci.org.au/&#34;&gt;NCI Australia&lt;/a&gt; computing facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsupervised learning in IRS-Assisted Monostatic Backscatter Systems: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/TMLCN.2024.3355317&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICASSP43922.2022.9746747&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention-Based BiLSTM Network for grant free NOMA: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/OJCOMS.2023.3292820&#34;&gt;[Journal]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federated learning for IoT networks:&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/JIOT.2022.3165596&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICCWorkshops53468.2022.9814533&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transfer learning for IRS: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/PIMRC50174.2021.9569500&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am keen to recruit more PhD students in this area. If you are interested, please contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realizable Synchronization Techniques - Unlocking the Potential of Future Wireless Networks</title>
      <link>/project/arcsynchronization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arcsynchronization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an ARC Discovery Project &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP140101133&#34;&gt;DP140101133&lt;/a&gt;. I was a lead-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel solutions for synchronization, wireless energy harvesting and wireless power transfer have been proposed to provide faster data rate, more reliable connectivity and prolonged network lifetime for heterogeneous cellular networks and energy-constrained ad hoc and sensor networks. The research outcomes were published in 1 book chapter, 12 journal papers and 15 conference papers. This includes one ISI Highly Cited Paper. The project involved successful collaboration with researchers from USA, Canada, France, Denmark and Hong Kong. The project provided research training to two postdocs and 3 PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAV and Satellite Communications</title>
      <link>/project/uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/uav/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic goal of this project is to investigate and propose novel strategies to leverage UAV and Satellite communications in 5G and beyond 5G communications. The project has resulted in two PhD theses, one undergraduate hons thesis, 8 journal papers and 5 conference papers so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific contributions include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stadium use case for UAV base station: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/JIOT.2018.2875166&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAV to support rapid information dissemination in a public safety scenario: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2962224&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trajectory modelling for cellular connected UAVs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICC40277.2020.9149407&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multitier UAV network with beam misalignments: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/JIOT.2023.3299279&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAV with caching and multicasting for file sharing in temporary events: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/TCOMM.2024.3369725&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAV aggregator for IoT monitoring network with reliability and latency requirements: &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAV-assisted maritime-satellite communication network: &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication in LEO Satellite-Based IoT Networks with UAV eavesdropper: &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UAV and SWIPT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICCWorkshops53468.2022.9814490&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an overview of how UAVs are currently being used in a wide range of industries across Australia, see here(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drones.gov.au/benefits-and-use-cases-drones)&#34;&gt;https://www.drones.gov.au/benefits-and-use-cases-drones)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-Fast and Secure Terahertz Communications for 6G Wireless Systems</title>
      <link>/project/arc_thz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arc_thz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing ARC Discovery Project DP230100878 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP230100878)&#34;&gt;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP230100878)&lt;/a&gt;. I am a co-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My specific contributions related to THz include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coverage analysis for THz: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/JSAC.2021.3071840&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/publication/&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved coverage analysis for THz:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/publication/&#34;&gt;[Journal paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub‐Band Assignment and Power Allocation With Beam Multiplexing and Aggregation in Terahertz Communications: &lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/publication/&#34;&gt;[Conference paper]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
