<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>past | </title>
    <link>/tags/past/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/past/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>past</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>past</title>
      <link>/tags/past/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Distributions and Modelling of Finite Wireless Networks</title>
      <link>/project/distance_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/distance_distributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Distance distributions can be applied to study important wireless network characteristics such as interference, outage probability, connectivity, routing, and energy consumption. They can also be applied in other branches of science, such as forestry, mathematics, operations research and material sciences. When a fixed and finite number of nodes are uniformly and independently distributed over a finite region such as a square or hexagon (polygon in general), the two important distance distributions are: 1) the pdf of the Euclidean distance between two nodes uniformly and independently distributed inside a polygon and 2) the pdf of the Euclidean distance between any arbitrary reference point and its nth neighbor node when N nodes are uniformly and independently distributed inside a polygon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our key contributions are available here(&lt;a href=&#34;https://s-durrani.com/software/)&#34;&gt;https://s-durrani.com/software/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Ultra‐Reliable and Sustainable Machine‐to‐Machine Communications</title>
      <link>/project/arc_mtom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arc_mtom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an ARC Discovery Project DP170100939(&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP170100939)&#34;&gt;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP170100939)&lt;/a&gt;. I was lead-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel solutions for data transmission, low-power backscatter transmission and wireless power transfer have been proposed to provide faster data rate, more reliable connectivity and prolonged network lifetime for machine-to-machine communications and Internet of Things devices and networks. The research outcomes were published in 27 journal papers and 20 conference papers. This includes several highly cited papers. The project involved successful collaboration with researchers from Canada, USA and Hong Kong. The project provided research training to one postdoc and 3 PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Spherical Geometry in Scientific and Engineering Data Processing</title>
      <link>/project/arc_spherical_signal_processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/arc_spherical_signal_processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an ARC Discovery Project DP150101011(&lt;a href=&#34;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP150101011)&#34;&gt;https://dataportal.arc.gov.au/NCGP/Web/Grant/Grant/DP150101011)&lt;/a&gt;. I was a co-CI in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novel solutions for sampling and spherical signal processing have been proposed to process data in real world applications such as biomedical imaging, astronomy and acoustic signal processing. The research outcomes were published in 8 journal papers and 12 conference papers. The project involved successful collaborations with researchers from Europe. The project provided research training to 4 postdocs and 2 PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD student and later postdoc Zubair Khalid was funded through this grant. Zubair Khalid was a part of the team which recently won the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://awards.acm.org/bell-climate&#34;&gt;Gordon Bell Prize for Climate Modelling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
