<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PhD | </title>
    <link>/tags/phd/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PhD</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>/tags/phd/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for International Students</title>
      <link>/project/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are considering to apply for PhD scholarship and admission at ANU, information on this page should be of interest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-wireless-communications-and-signal-processing-at-anu&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Wireless communications and Signal processing at ANU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Australian National University (ANU) is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s foremost research universities. Information about ANU&amp;rsquo;s national and international ranking is available &lt;a href=&#34;http://users.cecs.anu.edu.au/~Salman.Durrani/links.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://asp.cecs.anu.edu.au/research&#34;&gt;ASP research group&lt;/a&gt; in the Research School of Engineering at ANU actively conducts research in the fields of wireless communications and signal processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-international-postgraduate-research-scholarship-iprs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. International Postgraduate Research Scholarship (IPRS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPRS is an Australian government funded scholarship which provides tuition fee for top international students wanting to do PhD in Australia. Details about IPRS allocation, ANU IPRS requirements and application forms is available in the links on the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://users.cecs.anu.edu.au/~Salman.Durrani/research.html&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, international students also have to apply for additional scholarship (e.g. ANU PhD scholarship) to cover the living expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline for IPRS applications is &lt;strong&gt;31 August&lt;/strong&gt; (for PhD commencing in Feb./March next year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-academic-record&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Academic Record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPRS is an extremely competitive scholarship. Students must have a brilliant undergraduate academic record (generally speaking a 1st class honours with at least 85% marks) and need to be academically in the top 5% of their graduating class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete detail of academic honours and awards should be provided with the IPRS application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-research-experiencepotential&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Research Experience/Potential&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students applying for IPRS are generally expected to provide evidence of having undertaken research (in the form of published or submitted papers). This is especially relevant to students applying for IPRS on the basis of a completed Masters degree. For fresh undergraduate students, research potential can be demonstrated via outstanding academic record and projects/internships undertaken during the course of the degree. Any relevant work experience can also be used to demonstrate research capability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-ielts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. IELTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students must have excellent written and oral English communication skills. If English is not your native language, you need to provide evidence of English language ability, generally via an IELTS test result. For more details, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://policies.anu.edu.au/ppl/document/ANUP_000408&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-prospective-supervisor&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Prospective Supervisor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that students contact a prospective supervisor prior to submitting their IPRS application. A supervisor&amp;rsquo;s support can significantly increase the chances of scholarship success. Students should look at the staff web pages to gain information about on-going and future research projects and then contact prospective supervisors directly (via email) to discuss project opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-research-proposal&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Research Proposal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1-2 page research proposal is expected with an IPRS application. The proposal should identify the proposed project title and PhD supervisor and should be finalised in consultation with the PhD supervisor. It should briefly describe the research problem and key objectives. It can also briefly discuss any relevant issues such as reason for choosing ANU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-students-from-pakistan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Students from Pakistan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students from Pakistan are eligible to apply for &lt;a href=&#34;https://aei.gov.au/scholarships-and-fellowships/international-applicants/pages/international-applicants.aspx&#34;&gt;Endeavour scholarship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-students-from-china&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Students from China&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students from China are eligible to apply for &lt;a href=&#34;https://aei.gov.au/scholarships-and-fellowships/international-applicants/pages/international-applicants.aspx&#34;&gt;Endeavour scholarship&lt;/a&gt; as well as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anu.edu.au/students/scholarships-support/anu-csc-scholarship&#34;&gt;ANU-CSC scholarship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; Disclaimer:- This is a personal home page and the advice and contents do not represent official University views. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
